# Jeremy Donson

# Dev Ops Support Engineer

Address:

New York City, NY 10027

Phone:

718-710-9434

Email:

jjdonson@gmail.com (mailto:jjdonson@gmail.com)

Website:

http://www.urbanspectra.com (http://www.urbanspectra.com)

#### **About**

Dev ops support engineer focused on test-driven tooling and automation to facilitate preventive problem-solving. More than 10 years of hands-on development team support, including all infrastructure and platform testing. Skilled bash, mariadb and python programmer. Expert with performant data and web system scaling.

#### Skills

#### Certifications Held

- MySQL Database Administrator + Developer
- Oracle Database Administrator + Developer
- RedHat Linux Systems Administrator

#### **Technologies**

- · Git, Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket
- CloudForms / ManagelQ
- OpenShift
- OpenStack
- Docker, DockerSwarm
- Ceph, Redis, Memcached, MongoDB
- MySQL, PostgreSQL

#### Languages Supported

- \* Bash, Expert, 10+ years
- Python, 5+ years
- C/C++, Intermediate, 5+ years
- Ruby, Intermediate, 5+ years
- · Java, Intermediate, 5+ years

- Node.js, Novice, 2+ years
- Go, novice, 2+ years

#### Diagrams

- Analytical Workflow Modeling
- \* Federated LAN/WAN Security Models & Test Matrices
- Digital Ecosystems & Staffing
- Logical Network & System Models
- Physical Network & System Schematics
- Logical Process & Data Models
- Physical Process & Data Diagrams

#### Certifications Pending

- AWS Pro Architect
- \* RedHat CloudForms + OpenStack + OpenShift
- CoreOS / Project Atomic

### Work Experience

# **Thingr**

#### Founder and developer

2014 - Present

https://thingr.com (https://thingr.com)

Knowledge management, discovery and collaboration service. Startup project.

- Frontend and backend development.
- SOA (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Service-oriented\_architecture) architecture. Dockerized (https://docker.com/) containers.
- REST API server, distributed task queueing, web content extraction and analysis.
- Python's Pyramid web framework (http://www.pylonsproject.org/) and SQLAlchemy ORM framework.

### Simbin AB

#### **Senior Python Backend Programmer**

2012 - 2014

http://game.raceroom.com/ (http://game.raceroom.com/)

- Developed Cassandra-based systems: generic content metadata, user activity feeds,
- ElasticSearch-based content search.
- Designed and developed game content permission system for users to buy, lend, and try content from the store. Dynamic permissions based on time, availability nad user properties like location, owned content and role groups.
- Custom Go-based statistics server which aggregates context based game activities and achivements.

- Introduced better quality with strong TDD, continous integration and development focus.
- · Major role in design process of game features and services.

### Gemilo OY

#### **Python Web Developer**

2008 - 2012

http://www.gemilo.com (http://www.gemilo.com)

Front and back-end developement of large, multipurpose collaboration SaaS platform.

- Design and development on major system components: permission system, caching framework, comments and blogging systems.
- Development of in-house tools for Scrum management, server monitoring, Database migrations and more.
- Pylons web framework / PostgreSQL / Javascript.
- Strong TDD approach.

## Youplanet

#### Javascript frontend developer

2008

Contracting job to help build a traveling site.

- Javascript tools and components.
- · Google maps integration.
- Usability advisor.

# i123.pl

#### Founder, Python Developer

2006 - 2009

http://i123.pl (http://i123.pl)

Multiple service-oriented tools and a community portal. (video bookmarking, rss reader, TODO app, meta search engine).

- First big python project.
- www.i123.pl Meta search engine, aggregating and prioritizing polish content from Google, Yahoo, MSN Search and polish search engines.
- \* rss.i123.pl Personalized RSS feed reader.
- video.i123.pl Personalized video aggregator. Users could upload own videos or use services like Youtube, Google Video, Vimeo, Metacafe (and others) to keep and share their videos.
- \* tudu.i123.pl Javascript TODO app.

### **Stbit**

#### Founder, Python/PHP developer

Consulting and web development agency.

- Plan, design and develop PHP software.
- Web security consulting.

### **Projects**

### BetaFrontpage

#### Frontend and backend developer

8.2014

http://www.betafrontpage.com (http://www.betafrontpage.com)

BetaFrontpage lists startups frontpages. Full screenshots for inspiration and product discovery.

- Pyramid web framework (http://www.pylonsproject.org/).
- Docker (https://docker.com/) for screenshot grabbing service.

### Wwwino.pl

#### Developed web spider and search engine. Frontend and backend developement.

2014 - Present

http://wwwino.pl (http://wwwino.pl)

Wine search engine and price comparator for Polish wine consumers.

- Pyramid web framework (http://www.pylonsproject.org/).
- ElasticSearch.
- · Web scrapping.

### Piwwwo.pl

#### Frontend and backend developer

08-2014

http://piwwwo.pl (http://piwwwo.pl)

Piwwwo.pl is a beer journal and brewery database.

- Pyramid web framework (http://www.pylonsproject.org/).
- \* SQLAlchemy ORM framework.
- PostgreSQL database.

### Education

# Columbia University

2000 - 2002

### Interests

- Web and data systems scalability and performance.
- Development team onboarding, training and workflow analytics.
- · Logical data modeling, architecture and physical storage engineering.
- Arts, Maths, Sciences, Education
- Jazz http://google.com
- Cooking
- Gardening

© Jeremy Donson I Download MSWord (Jeremy\_Donson\_Resume.doc) I Download PDF (Jeremy\_Donson\_Resume.pdf) | Print | Top

Source on github (https://github.com/jjdonson/resume)